From: Les Robertson <Les.Robertson@cern.ch>
Date: March 8, 2007 1:57:40 PM CST
To: Ruth Pordes <ruth@fnal.gov>
Subject: WLCG - OSG meeting San Diego 8 March 2007

Issues for WLCG wrt OSG.
	•	The formal relationship between WLCG and OSG is that the OSG Director is in the management (executive) board of WLCG. The OSG Director is also now the US representative in the Grid Deployment Board.
	•	In addition the relationships set up in the pre-OSG period are still in place - US HEP ATLAS and CMS have representatives on the Overview (oversight) Board (as providers of Tier-1 facilities).
	•	WLCG sites are almost all now part of either EGEE or OSG - and so the relationship between these two projects is of prime importance for technical and operational issues - in particular:   --  VDT distribution and support - (VDT is the base of the EGEE middleware distribution - gLite) -       Day to day situtation is working well, but we do have to do something communicating medium term       concerns and longer term strategy.   --  Interoperability - major work done in 2005/06. While this does not appear as a major concern at the       moment for LCG experiments it is important to keep these options open, maintaining the current level        of interoperability (GLUE, CEs, ..).       (Miron - things are confusing - not clear which requirements come from experiments and which come       from WLCG, and who or what is responsible. Agreed that Ruth will draw up an initial list of items and       we see how to proceed.)   --  common operational procedures  - joint weekly operations meeting. A a series of joint workshops has       been held, but the series seems to have stalled for the moment.        (It seems that EGEE has stalled - this year and last year the North American meetings were cancelled        by EGEE - Les to follow up.)
	•	More direct WLCG relationship - largely driven through WLCG's Grid Deployment Board - this deals with facilities issues, initiating things that require agreement with the infrastructure projects.   --  Joint Security Group - this is a very important activity, which stiil has work to do at the policy level        (Don says that he thinks that this does not go far enough, sticking at the level where common agreements       can be made)   --  OPN - networking for the major data flows - this is complicated in the US. This is not the direct concern        of OSG.        (Don says that the OPN chair, who does an excellent job of preparing the OPN operation, is too restrictive        in the wider discussion.)
	•	The GDB is important this year as we try to get everything together for the startup - compromising between product developers, experiments and sites. While it is easy to map GDB decisions on to EGEE responsibilities this is not the case for OSG. It is important that Ruth keeps an eye on this and makes it clear to WLCG when GDB decisions cause difficulties for OSG.
   
____________________________________________ Les Robertson LHC Computing Grid Project Leader Information Technology Department European Organisation for Nuclear Research CERN                         phone: +41 22 767 49 16 CH-1211 Geneva 23        gsm: +41 76 487 01 80
 
